hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and in this podcast we
talk about ways for you to grow in your
life and in your business if you are a
coach Mentor trainer and you want to
know how do I get more clients and how
do I make more money and have things
come together the way that I want them
to that's what what this podcast is all
about you're in the right place now what
I want to talk about here today is part
of the mental battles that we deal with
and how to overcome those and a strategy
that I've found recently that I that has
made a huge difference for me in my own
Journey number one you know I've talked
about over the years I've had uh trauma
and liing beliefs and even dealt with
ADHD and very various things that have
caused me trouble with building my
business that people deal with that is
very real that maybe we don't talk about
but I've learned how to show up
confidently I didn't show up confidently
on camera for years I've learned how to
communicate well with people I've
learned how to lead how to run a company
how to do hard things that quite frankly
just no matter how much training I took
didn't come naturally to me and I was
overwhelmed constantly by doing these
things and I hear people all the time
say Jeremiah I'm overwhelmed constantly
by these things and so here's one of the
number one things that I can tell you is
that you have to learn the art of
stepping into a joyful State of
Mind a sort of like a childlike playful
State of Mind here's what that looks
like though practically you know is that
you have hope for how things are going
to turn out well for you that you get
into actually feeling the end outcome
working out before it happens and this
can actually be kind of difficult and
very hard and almost like your brain
doesn't want to go there because it
looks at reality and it looks what at
what's really going on in our lives and
it says I'm not going to go there I
can't go there because it's not true and
so I'm a realist I'm somebody who looks
at things realistically and then what
I've done is I've actually learned and
sort of reverse engineered this into how
can I make this work as a framework for
my life for my business and what I can
share with other people is that you have
to um figure out how to get there get
into it joyful State of Mind as far as
that goes now not every day are you
going to experience that in fact most of
the time when we wake up in the morning
we don't experience that but there are
techniques and strategies that can get
you into that state of mind and that's
what I've been realizing is that for me
to show up as best as I can even
recording this podcast I was struggling
to get into the right mindset to share
with you what I wanted to
share and so what I had to do is I had
to just take a few minutes and breathe
and like calm my nervous system down and
relax a little bit and you might say I
don't have time for
that I would implore you that you don't
have time not
to is that when it comes to building
your business taking 5 to 10 minutes to
reset yourself and by the way sometimes
it's setting a time limit on that
learning how to not get so amped up in
situations in your life have you ever
noticed like when you wake up in the
morning maybe you feel joyful or you
don't depends on how you what are you
focusing on when you go to bed whatever
we focus on in our Mind's Eye and in our
energy ends up coming out in our actions
and so if I'm focusing on how all the
bad stuff is happening and what I don't
like that's going on and what I wish was
different all I end up
experiencing is
like I'm slogging through mud trying to
get to where I want to go and I have no
Focus I have no drive I have no
motivation and all I can actually see is
what's not working and so I'm in a
critical state of mind and so just
shifting and training your brain to
shift into a positive not just
positivity but a joyful
expectant gratitude based excited I'm
expecting things to work out well I have
a vis a vision that I'm going to record
like for a podcast like this I have a
vision that I'm going to record a
podcast that's going to impact people
and they're going to love it and and and
actually seeing people enjoying the
content and coming into it from that
perspective of visualizing in my mind's
eye the most positive outcome not that I
finished the podcast see that's one of
the keys it's not just me visualizing oh
I did the podcast I could do that in my
sleep that's easy but that it actually
went well and that it was exciting and
that it was fun and that I enjoyed what
I did when it comes to making video
content when it comes to communicating
well over video this is one of the key
aspects of being able to do so is
because your energy gets transferred to
People by what they see in your body
language and your facial expression and
so if you're so focused or or like this
it it doesn't translate in a way that is
going to connect it's going to repel
people that you want to actually connect
with it's going to make people think
something is off as far as that goes and
when it comes to our Marketing in our
businesses as coaches and as mentors how
we communicate our body language how we
show up the tone of voice what what is
showing up on our expression as well as
our bodily expression because the
expression goes beyond just what what's
on the face but also how we show up
physically our tone of our tonality the
way that we're structuring words are we
defensive are we trying to prove
ourselves all of this comes together and
subconsciously those that listen to us
those that are reading our marketing
those that are checking out all the
different things to to to see is this
somebody I want to work with people end
up making decisions if they want to work
with us based on how are we showing up
in those ways and so if you can tune and
align yourself to be able to show up
well
that changes everything for you some of
the ways that I used to try I I did is
sometimes I might play a video game or
watch a movie or read a book or
something like that those don't always
work sometimes you'll go for a walk
exercise can help really well as well
making sure that you're eating a good
diet something that has Whole Foods
Green Foods something that makes sure
that you have enough water as well all
of these factors play into the
neurotransmitters in our mind and how we
actually show up and that allows us to
either attract or repel the people that
we want to work with and so this is why
this is one of those number one big
mistakes that I see the people make when
it comes to building their business or
trying to get clients or trying to do
the things that they want to do is that
they end up just
really
like they're so caught up in what they
want to avoid they're so caught up in
what's not working they're so caught up
in in the feelings of everything that's
going on around them that they're not
present that they're not actually
consistent and it's not somebody that
people actually want to listen to or
spend time with for your marketing to be
effective for you to be a good speaker
teacher author trainer your energy has
to show up in a way that draws people to
you in a way that gets people want to
want to be on board with you so again
this can also come from your faith this
can come from prayer this can come from
meditation as well one of the things
that I like to do is I have certain
levels of meditation that I'll go
through is one of them is I'll start
with paying attention to my breath I I
did this a little bit ago actually as I
sat over here and I paid attention to my
breath the rising and falling of my
lungs as I breathed in that was stage
one number two I just kind of mentally
scanned from my head to my toes and then
back up again and then I started to
notice different changes inside of my my
feeling and stuff like that then what I
started to do is I started to focus on
feeling gratitude mentally so I so I
focus on just the being present scanning
my body and then gratitude and then from
that gratitude I start focusing in on
what is the task at hand that I have to
do okay one of the things you want to be
aware of is your brain as you start to
meditate your brain might try to look at
all the stuff that's going wrong you
just want to let those those thoughts
pass you on by and you want to be
intentional in what you're doing so once
you get present and what you can get
focused in on scanning your body and the
breath this can take maybe 5 to 10
minutes sometimes that and you might say
I don't have 5 to 10 minutes sometimes I
get it this can actually literally you
might like you might feel itchy or
tingly or you might feel like this is
too much or it's like over you're over
stimulated by trying to sit there and do
this that right there shows you why we
need to do that because your nervous
system we want to bring that into
alignment of a state of calm
peace and presence and so when we can do
this and then we can start to get
intentional around Joy gratitude
happiness I'm excited I have hope for
the future it trains and tunes the
reticular activating system of your
brain to look for all the good stuff and
so then when we go out there to do the
thing that might be hard or that we're
procrastinating on or that has been hard
for us it literally unlocks the
creativity in your mind to be able to go
out there and do those things again you
can learn more about different stuff
like this there's different
practices some are more spiritual than
others I tend to be more focused on the
physical about how I'm feeling
physically and and just what is like do
I feel anxious energy or have I calmed
that down to I literally I feel at ease
at
rest and and I even use this when I go
to sleep as well it helps me fall asleep
now you don't want to fall asleep but
you're doing this when you have work to
do this can actually energize you when
you have work to do by focusing
intentionally on that joy and that
happiness and where you're going with
things okay so again this is what I have
found is that by getting present we end
up detaching from the past or or the
future even and we start getting present
and we start visualizing what is the
next thing that I got to do what is the
outcome that I want to happen from this
maybe I got to take a course okay I'm
not just going to focus on taking the
course I'm going to have an set an
intention of this course is going to I'm
going to I'm going to know all the great
things that I need to know about getting
this accomplished and so I I move one
step further from the task that I have
to visualize into what is the feeling
and emotion to start to experience that
at the end of it so I calm the nervous
system down I breathe in and out through
that I do the me the meditation
breathing and then I focus in on what is
that outcome that I want to get to as to
how it feels inside of me I do this
after I feel that calm and that peace
after I feel that ease as far as that
goes now depending on let's say that I
had a really stressful morning sometimes
that can take me 30 minutes to do but I
will tell you this in my experience it's
worth it taking that 30 minutes because
when we don't we end up showing up in a
way that is that is just not our best we
end up showing up in a way that is not
going to connect with people well and so
this is what I have just I found is that
there's certain tasks
that yes you got to do them you got to
dive into them we can't take 30 minutes
to do them I totally understand that but
I'll say this when it comes to me
showing up on video or making video
content that's generally where I like to
go is I like to really focus on calming
the nervous system down and getting into
the most positive excited happiest State
of Mind mentally and then that gets me
ready to be able to
communicate and work with people now one
of the things that I love to do is I
love to help coaches and mentors that
they are struggling to get leads they're
struggling to use Facebook ads they're
struggling to get their funnels up and
one of the things that people tell me is
those can be really really overwhelming
to do those things this practice is one
of those things that you can also do
when you go into doing and building your
funnels and it's something that I train
and teach a lot of my clients to do in
my client growth accelerator program
this is one of the tactics that I teach
them is get into a childlike playful
State of Mind do do something that's fun
for you to get your mind off of the
thing that you're trying to avoid or
that you don't want to experience and
learning to take control of your
thoughts learning to where your thoughts
don't go every one way your feelings and
emotions and internal bodily uh anxiety
doesn't control you this is something
that not a lot of people talk about and
I think that even traditional therapy
can sometimes fail people at I I've been
working with a therapist for over 3
years it's helped me tremendously but I
found myself ruminating on all the stuff
I wanted to avoid instead of having hope
for where I wanted to go and as soon as
I shifted out of that and into being a
co-creator of the world around me and
what I wanted to experience and started
saying okay I'm going to make this
happen the way I want it to happen
everything started shifting in a
positive direction for me and I can tell
you it'll happen for you as well all
right so listen this has been the grow
Your Life podcast if you've liked it
please share this episode with somebody
I know that it's going to imp imp
somebody in your life and don't just
hold this to yourself share this episode
so that it can also impact somebody else
as well and if you are a coach or Mentor
I'd love to work with you in my
accelerator program jump in there and
let's get your business growing talks
[Music]
[Applause]